Antonio Martinez

antonios.martinez.dev@gmail.com +506 6417-3469 Heredia, Costa Rica https://martinezantonio.github.io/

Summary

Full-stack web developer with 7+ years experience participating in the complete product development lifecycle of successfully launched web applications. From backend programming, coding in PHP to frontend programming, coding in JavaScript, Angular CLI, HTML5, and CSS3.

Good understanding of object-oriented programming and MVC pattern design. Excellent debugging skills and good webmaster concepts in terms of development environment setup (lamp, wamp, SSL, DNS, IP configuration, Cloudflare).

Good understanding of web services and SOA related standards like REST / OAuth / JSON.

A day in my life may consist of: prepping a new project in Angular CLI with basic assets, fixing some front-end bugs, adding an API Rest endpoint, MySQL database design, create some WordPress plugin from scratch, configuring a unit or UI test library, setting up a build or deployment plan, provisioning a test tier machine or feature work.

Experience

Web Developer

Jazz Gaming Solutions • San Jose, Costa Rica

01/2018 - 09/2020

I was responsible for developing, implementing and maintaining mostly internal web applications. I collaborated with technical and business staff in the design, development, testing, implementation and production support of enterprise applications in PHP and Angular CLI.

We primarily used MEAN Stack. 40% of my work was doing front end development, 40% back end development and the remaining 20% was dev-ops/sys admin related tasks.

Web Developer

PROFI • San Jose, Costa Rica

04/2014 - 02/2017

At PROFI, I was working on PHP, WordPress, Javascript (Angular CLI and vanilla).

Some of my web apps included: Custom WordPress plugins and widgets, digital menuboards, mobile/desktop business dashboards, online website plugins, and APIs integrations. I was also responsible for the managing my team's web infrastructure, SEO, marketing and website design.

Email templates design in HTML and CSS. SMTP and mailPHP email templates sending.

Web Developer

CIP Reporting • Virginia, United States

08/2016 - 06/2017

At my current position, I am working on a large reporting system for casinos. Giving them maintenance and programming new reports and new functions. We use technologies such as PHP 5.3v, MySQL databases, jQuery, CSS, and AJAX.

In addition to full-stack development, I also working on a lot of dev-ops tasks. I have helped set up a lot of our unit, UI, and build/deploy plans.

Email templates design in HTML and CSS. SMTP and mailPHP email templates sending.

Web Developer

Netsoft • San Jose, Costa Rica

03/2013 - 02/2014

At Netsoft, I was working on PHP API REST and SOAP Integrations. I also developed API from scratch.

Designed front-end of web application using HTML/CSS and Servlets.

Email templates design in HTML and CSS. SMTP and mailPHP email templates sending.

Technologies

- PHP
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- JQuery
- Git

- MySQL
- Angular
- CSS
- HTML5

Education

High school

Liceo Ingeniero Manuel Benavides Rodriguez • San Jose, San Jose

Currently completing courses in computer science, robotics and statistics

Languages

Spanish
English

Projects

https://martinezantonio.github.io

https://plive.ganchrow.com

https://www.cipreporting.com

https://venturetech.ml

https://jazzsports.ag

https://scoresandodds.com

https://toyotacr.com

https://stayincostarica.com

https://tabacon.com

https://guachipelin.com

https://bestwesterjacobeach.com

02/2015